This edged weapon defense is a straight stab, once again.
It's a wrist control.
We previously went to the outside.
Let's say, that we're going to be forced to the inside this time, and I come in.
I still am going to hook it and catch it.
I don't want catch the blade, obviously.
That'll make for a short defense.
I want to grab as much as I can here.
Daniel's already spread out, but as with our other technique, he's not going to leave his hand out there.
He's going to start to fight to get it back, and as he does, I'm going to go with him, and spiral that hand back around inside, turn this completely back into him and yank the knife away.
Now, I can either throw him to the ground.
I can kick him in the leg.
I can blast him in the side with the hilt of this other knife.
The thousand things I can do, but before we do that we've got to get the knife away.
So I'm, inside.
He starts to pull it back.
It's fine, I go with it.
Here, I have the whole hand locked up.
He's exposed, his center is raised up.
Twist that, grab the blade here, turn it out of his hand.
More than likely, I would've simply throw him to the ground, project him as far away from me as possible.
Before any of that happens, you've got to be off the line.
He pulls back, and we go.
Zonk you, for wrist control, inside wrist turn, pull it away, slam into the ground, and that is a good technique for an inside wrist control.